securebrowser.com 2016-06-28

# Privacy Policy | Safer Technologies

Welcome to Safer.com (the “Site”), a website operated by Safer Technologies Inc. (“Safer”, “we”, “us”, or “our”). We provide the Secure Browser and related third party software and services (“Safer Products”) for download by our users. We are aware of the trust you place in us and our responsibility to protect your privacy. As part of this responsibility, we provide this privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) to let you know what information we collect, how we use it, share it and protect it.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy is subject to revision from time to time on a going-forward basis. We will post any revised version of the Privacy Policy on this page. Continued use of the Site or our Products following such changes will indicate your acknowledgement of such changes and agreement to be bound by the terms and conditions of such changes. Accordingly, we encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy.

**Personal Information**

As used in this Privacy Policy, the phrase “Personal Information” means information that is used or intended to be used to personally identify an individual, like your name, address, e-mail address, or phone number. In some countries, a computer’s IP Address may also be considered to be Personal Information.

**Information Collected Through the Safer Site**

_The Information We Gather from Site Visitors and How We Use It_.

_Personal Information_ – When you access the Safer Site, we do not collect Personal Information from you, unless you knowingly provide it, including when you register for an account on the Site, provide feedback, or request information. We use your Personal Information to administer your account and provide you customer support and services, to send communications and administrative emails, to respond to your inquiries, to market our Products to you, and to improve the quality of the Site and Products. We also reserve the right to use and share Personal Information of Site Visitors to diagnose Site errors and malfunctions, to investigate and report instances of prohibited user behavior and to respond to legal processes.

_Anonymous Information_ – When you access our Site, we may use server log files to automatically record information about your Site visit. The log files may include your Internet Protocol address, browser type, the date and time of your request, and the web pages you have visited. We use log files to analyze the traffic to our Site, understand how users interact with our Site, for internal reporting purposes and to diagnose Site errors. Additionally, we may also utilize Cookies when you access our Site. “Cookies” are small pieces of information that a website sends to your computer’s web browser while you are viewing a website. We may use both session Cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent Cookies (which stay on your browser until you delete them) to improve your experience on the Site (e.g., by keeping you logged in). Our cookies do not collect Personal Information. Cookies can provide information about your activity on the Site. We use collected information to improve the quality of the Site and our Products, to keep you logged into a session and track the pages you have visited; and to market our Products to you, and for our general business purposes. Persistent Cookies can be removed by following your Internet browser help file directions. If you choose to disable Cookies, you may not be able to use certain features of the Site. Safer may also use a number of third party services, such as Google Analytics, for the data collected from Site Visitors. End Users are encouraged to click on the following link to become familiar with Google’s privacy policy and practices applicable to Google Analytics and the options available to End-Users.

**Do Not Track Policy**

The Safer.com website is configured to respond to browser-generated do not track signals. Safer makes no representations regarding the do not track policies of the websites or services included with or accessible through the Site or Products and you are directed to the privacy policies of each such respective service or website for information on their policies.

**Information Collected Through Secure  Browser**

When an End User installs and uses Secure Browser, certain information is collected from such End User, and this section describes how we collect, use and share such information. PLEASE NOTE THAT OUR PARTNERS AND SEARCH PROVIDERS MAY INDEPENDENTLY COLLECT INFORMATION ABOUT YOU, AND THIS PRIVACY POLICY DOES NOT GOVERN THEIR COLLECTION, USE AND DISCLOSURE OF SUCH INFORMATION. PLEASE CONSULT THEIR PRIVACY POLICIES AND TERMS OF SERVICES BEFORE USING SAFER PRODUCTS.

_Universally Unique Identifier_ – When you install the Secure Browser, a universally unique identifier (“UUID”) is created that identifies that particular installation of the Secure Browser software and the identification of the computer where it is installed. This information does not identify a particular person. Safer uses this information for updates, debugging, reporting and system maintenance.

_Search Queries_ – The Secure Browser includes search functionality from a Search Provider selected by Safer. When you enter a search query using the search function included in the Secure Browser, your query is transmitted to the Search Provider. The Search Provider’s use of the search query, any results and other information collected, used or disclosed associated with the search is governed by their privacy policy. Safer does not maintain a record of you search queries, although the Secure Browser installed on your computer may maintain a history of your recent search activity to improve your browsing experience. You may delete this locally-stored search history, or prevent such local storage by enabling the private browsing mode, at any time through the user controls contained within the Secure Browser. Any time you use the Secure Browser to access a Search Provider, such as by sending a search query, the Secure Browser may send the Search Provider standard, limited information including some or all of the following: your Internet Protocol address, browser type, browser language, and the date and time of your request. Our current Search Providers include, but are not limited to the following, and their privacy policies may be found at the URLs listed below:

Google (<https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>)  
Yahoo! (<https://policies.yahoo.com/us/en/yahoo/privacy/products/search/index.htm>)  
Bing (<https://www.microsoft.com/privacystatement/default.aspx>)  
Ask (<http://about.ask.com/privacy-policy/>)  
Amazon ([http://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html/?ie=UTF8&nodeId=468496](http://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html/?ie=UTF8&nodeId=468496))  
DuckDuckGo (<https://duckduckgo.com/privacy>)  
MySearch ([http://search.mysearch.com/content/html/mys/documents/pp/en/privacy.html](https://search.mysearch.com/content/html/mys/documents/pp/en/privacy.html))

_Search Auto-Suggest_ – The Search Provider may also provide functionality whereby search queries are automatically suggested by the Search Provider when you enter a search query. These recommendations are generated based upon the internal anonymous query database of maintained by the Search Provider. Additionally, if you have a separate account with the Search Provider, to which you are logged-in when transmitting a search query, the Search Provider may take into consideration non-personally identifying information about you in its database when generating search query recommendations. This information is not stored by Safer.

_Bookmarks_ – The Secure Browser allows users to bookmark web pages for quick reference and access. Secure Browser may record this information and when End-Users interact with these bookmarks. This information does not contain personally identifying information and is not disclosed by Safer to third parties.

_Usage Reporting_ – The Secure Browser automatically transmits information to us on how End-User interact with our software. We use this information in aggregate form to improve our internal operations and software. End-Users may opt out of this transmission of information by adjusting their preferences within the Secure Browser, except for information regarding the version of the Secure Browser in use and the browser extensions that are enabled. The browser version and extension information does not contain personally identifying information and is used by us to understand the versions of the Secure Browser that are in use and to provide critical software updates.

_Geolocation Data_ – The Secure Browser allows users to share their geolocation information with third-party websites and services. Users may share geolocation by enabling this feature, which is provided by Google. Use of your geolocation information will be governed by the applicable terms of service and privacy policies of Google and the third party websites and services with whom you choose to share this information and users are encouraged to review such terms and polices before sharing their geolocation information. Safer does not collect or store End-User geolocation information.

_Third Party Sign On_ – The Secure Browser may provide the option for you to sign onto one or more third party services (such as Facebook or Twitter). To use this feature, you will need to provide personal information, such as you user name and password, in order to link and sign onto the third-party service. This information is not be transmitted to us and your use of this feature is at your option.

**Information Sharing – Personal Information**

_Sharing of Personal Information_ : We limit the amount of Personal Information we collect from End-Users and only share Personal Information with other companies or individuals that help us provide our services. We also share Personal Information with third parties if we have a good faith belief that access, use, or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to: (a) satisfy applicable law, regulation, legal process or an enforceable governmental request, (b) enforce the applicable Terms of Service, Privacy Policy or other agreement with Safer, including investigation of potential violations thereof, (c) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, or (d) protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of Safer, its users or the public as required or permitted by law; with any of our subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under common control with us, in which case we will require them to honor this policy. Additionally, in the event we go through a business transition such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, your Personal Information may be among the assets transferred; and with third parties to whom you ask us to send Personal Information.

YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE PROCESSED BY US IN THE COUNTRY WHERE IT WAS COLLECTED AS WELL AS OTHER COUNTRIES (INCLUDING THE UNITED STATES) WHERE LAWS REGARDING PROCESSING OF PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE LESS STRINGENT THAN THE LAWS IN YOUR COUNTRY. BY USING THIS SITE AND PROVIDING ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION OR BY USING SAFER PRODUCTS, YOU ARE CONSENTING TO THE TRANSFER OF DATA FROM YOUR COUNTRY TO A COUNTRY THAT HAS LESS STRINGENT LAWS, AND THE PROCESSING OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION IN CONFORMANCE WITH THIS POLICY.

**Security Limitations**

We take reasonable security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. These include internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, as well as physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems where we store personal data. However, while we take reasonable steps to protect information against security breaches and unauthorized access, no data transmission over the internet can be guaranteed to be totally secure, and therefore we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information collected, stored or transmitted by us, THE SAFER PRODUCTS or parties that supply services to us.

**Information Disclosed by You to Third Parties**

If you disclose information to third parties, the use and disclosure restrictions contained in this Privacy Policy will not apply to any third party. We do not control the privacy and security practices of third parties, and you are subject to the privacy policies and other terms of use of those third parties where applicable. The Site may contain links to other websites that are not owned or controlled by us. We have no control over, do not review and are not responsible for the privacy policies of or content displayed on such other websites. When you click on such a link, you will leave our Site and go to another site. During this process, another entity may collect Personal Information or Anonymous Information from you. The Site may also contain links to other websites controlled by us but which operates under different privacy policies. Please review the privacy policy and other applicable terms of any new site you visit.

**Children**

We do not knowingly collect or maintain information from individuals who are under 13 years of age, and no part of our Site or Products are designed to attract people under the age of 13. Protecting the privacy of children is very important to us. If we obtain knowledge that a user is under the age of 13, we will take steps to remove that user’s information from our databases. If you are under 13 years of age, we ask that you do not install Safer Products or make use of Safer’s services. If you are between 13 and 18 years of age, we ask that you involve your parents in the process of reviewing of our Products and services, and applicable Privacy Policy, Terms of Service and End-User License Agreement and installing our Products.

**Contact Us**

If you have questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy, please contact us through our [contact form](http://www.safer.com/contact/).

Last revision: October 20, 2015
